Guide to the Child Study Club of Ithaca records, 1901-1983.
Child Study Club of Ithaca records, 1901-1983
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Child Study Club of Ithaca records, 1901-1983.
2932
Child Study Club of Ithaca (N.Y.)
1.4 cubic ft.
Minutes; constitutions, bylaws, and amendments; correspondence; a history; financial records; yearbooks; rosters; pamphlets; hand outs; and clippings.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of the Child Study Club of Ithaca dealing with the club's interests and activities, including the mental and physical development of children; theories of child behavior; children's entertainment; local organizations for children, such as Girl Scouts and West Side House.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Child Study Club of Ithaca was founded in 1901 "for the study of the child and his needs."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes minutes of the Child Study Club of Ithaca dealing with the club's interests and activities, including the mental and physical development of children; theories of child behavior; children's entertainment; local organizations for children, such as Girl Scouts and West Side House; constitutions, bylaws, and amendments, 1921-1973; correspondence of the Secretary with other organizations, 1923-1965, including the City Federation of Women's Organizations, the American Red Cross, Ithaca Better Films Council, Tompkins County Tuberculosis and Public Health Association, and the League of Women Voters of Tompkins County; a history of the club by Lucille H. Gunkel, 1969; financial records, 1930-1961; yearbooks and rosters, 1903-1976; pamphlets, hand outs, and clippings.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Child Study Club of Ithaca (N.Y.); Gunkel, Lucille H.; American Red Cross.; City Federation of Women's Organizations.; Girl Scouts of the United States of America.; Ithaca Better Films Council.; League of Women Voters of Tompkins County (Tompkins County, N.Y.); Tompkins County Tuberculosis and Public Health Association.; West Side House.
Subjects:
Children's literature.; Child psychology.; Women--Societies and clubs.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.); Tompkins County (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Constitutions.; Bylaws (administrative records); Yearbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Account book, 1925-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Brochures, member notices, 1950-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Child Study Club anniversary cake photograph, ca. 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Child Study Club history, [1969] (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Constitution of the Child Study Club of Ithaca, N.Y., 1921-1922, 1956, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1923-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Health concerns and information, 1915-1952 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Internal Revenue Service, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Invoices, bank statements, cancelled checks, contributions, 1954-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Membership lists, 1903-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous club information, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Musical development programs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Old business, new business, recommendations, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Tompkins County Public Library, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Minutes of meetings (also available on microfilm), Mar. 9, 1901-Apr. 9, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Minutes of meetings, 1915-1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Minutes of meetings, 1919-1923 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Minutes of meetings, 1923-1925 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Minutes of meetings, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Minutes of meetings, Oct. 15, 1925-Dec. 6, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Minutes of meetings, Oct. 3, 1929-May 15, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Minutes of meetings, 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Minutes of meetings, Oct. 10, 1935-June 1939 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Minutes of meetings, Oct. 13, 1939-May 1945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Minutes of meetings, Sept. 1945-Apr. 1954 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Minutes of meetings, Nov. 10, 1955-Feb. 21, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Minutes of meetings, Feb. 13, 1969-Apr. 10, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Minutes of meetings, May 1973-Apr. 20, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Minutes of meetings, Sept. 13, 1979-Apr. 9, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Yearbooks of the Child Study Club, 1939-1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Members' and Program Committee booklets, 1903-1942 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Packet of address cards for members (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Three checking account books, 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 34)